# Liu, Teng-Yuan (Shuk Liu)

<u>biz.shuk@gmail.com</u>, Skype: initialshuk <u>Linkedin</u>, TW (886) 0902-398163

Birth:1986/07

Summary last updated: 2021-02-07

Full-Stack engineer aim services on the internet, mostly worked on back-end and experienced in web app, game development, analysis, AWS, CI/CD, and Agile methodology. Working on Linux(Ubuntu) or Mac and having deep understanding of VCS. Designing scalable system with higher availability is part of my job and analyzing pros and cons of technique depends on resources. Also knowing well on concepts/layers/protocols. And cooperate with Product Manager to analyze business requirement for tech spec including give a proper schedule for those tasks.

## **Education**

- M.S. in CS, National Central University, Jongli , Taiwan, 2009/09 2011/06, June. (Java, PHP)
- B.S. in CS, National Dong-Hua University, Hualien, Taiwan, 2004/09 2009/06, Jan. (C, C++, PHP)

## **Skills**

Certificate: AWS - Solution Architect - associate (2018/08), TOEIC: 830(2019/01)

Language: Java (Spring Boot, MVC, Batch, Data), Golang, js(Reactjs, Redux), Bash, SQL

PHP, Perl, HTML5/CSS (SASS), Terraform(AWS infra)

Server as a admin: Linux, Git, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Apache HTTP, BIND

Server as a user: Kubernetes, Mysql(schema design), Mongo, ElasticSearch, Memcached, Gitlab-runner, Rundeck Concept: OO, CI/CD, MVC, Network, RWD, Cache, HA, Scalability, BDD, Agile, Lean, Scrum

## **Work Experience**

#### Engineer | Innova Solutions | Songshan, TW

 $2017/02 \sim$ 

Cloud solution provider. In this branch, it's BOT for Change Health Care(CHC) in U.S.

- Work on AWS, Java (Spring Boot, MVC, Batch, Data), Golang, ElasticSearch, Scrum.
  Small Scrum team in US. Cross-team communication, Production support
- Manage half of the team (5-8p including QA) in 3 months and give suggestions to projects.
- Lead new re-org team to form and catch up US team with scrum team best practice
- Integration of Enterprise Solution in CHC
- Traversed whole stack of legacy system and migrated some to new cloud architecture(not app) successfully.
- Eliminating security issues diagnosed by Fortify
- Tuning java app through jstack jstat jmap in rare cases.
- Built a framework including all fundamental services leveraged to keep AWS Lambda function simple.
- Construct persistent file process architecture to process batch files and other massive processing with Async.

## Cloud Engineer | Shanghai Droi Tech Co. Ltd. | Taipei 101, TW

2015/07 - 2016/05

Internet company, 500+ people, from device hardware to backend as a cloud application solution (e.g. parse.com)

- Worked on Bash, Lua, Linux, Nginx, Docker, Jenkins, Ansible, Kubenetes, Mongo, PostgreSQL.
- Model "Backend As A Service" arch including app commit flow and integrate with Jenkins toward Kubernetes.
- End to end test framework for developers on the platform, also including syntax check, api detected, and request profiling.
- Cli tool to make linear version control, let user manage their own code simply.

#### Game and BI developer | Gamesofa Inc. | Taipei, TW

2012/11 - 2015/04

Online Game company, 200 people, self-made games including Mahjong, Poker, FPS, and RPG

- Worked on PHP, Perl, HTML5, Javascript, AngularJS, CSS, Linux, Apache, Mysql, Memcache.
- Get requirements from PM, check the scope in each small sprint. Eventually, collaborate with QA and delivery.
- Win8 App "Godgame big two" by HTML5, integrate billing services, interact with back-end, adjust UI.
- Responsible for "<u>Godgame Texas Hold'em</u>" server side events and features, e.g. general friend list for multiple games, and fix bugs.
- Omaha game rule is to pick in two sets, one pick 2 in 4 and other pick 3 in 5, to combine biggest card type and compare with others people, using hash and combined with card type probability to reduce the performance issue.
- Developed survey system and deploy to different region to solve global location latency issue ,and customized options for ordered sequential options avoiding making useless data.
- User analyzing system showing user retention rate, payment and activated situations with selected group. It's easy for product manager and marketing specialist. And we may do some A/B testing for groups of user.
- Refactor and maintain existing systems, customer service system.

## Web developer | National Central University | Jongli, Taiwan

2010/03-2011/06

- [PHP] Setup websites, bypass library system for ebook search, saving \$20000 at least and maintaining fee
- [PHP] Refactor facility application system

## **Projects and self-study**

- Google C++ education (06/2016 06/2016)
- Lee Code Python, C++, javascript (05/2016 present)
- Personal web site React, RWD(04/2015 06/2015) Free code camp HTML5 (09/2015 11/2015)

## Other Experience

## Working Holiday | | Europe

 $06/2016 \sim 02/2017$ 

Go Ireland with Working Holiday VISA. This VISA can participate any roles in Ireland. But even I resolved this ambiguous policy with WHA Immigration Office. It didn't get recognized for permanent SE role. After stayed for 80 days and took 30 days for Euro tour, I backed to my Taiwan. I started to recalled some role's criteria which I saw in this trip and studied more algorithms.

- Participated language exchange community
- Lee Code with Python, C++, javascript (2016/05- present)
- Google C++ education (2016/06 2016/06)

## Break and Self-Study | | Taiwan

2015/04 - 2015/06

- Free code camp with HTML5 (2015/09 2015/11)
- Personal web site http://shuk.info/ with ReactJS, RWD (2015/04 2015/06) (Domain is not available anymore)

#### Alternative civilian service | Dept. of Civil Servant Development | Taipei, TW

2011/12 - 2012/11

• [PHP] Assist staffs to discuss system spec of *Taipei e-campus*, discuss priorities with third party engineers.

#### Housekeeper | Motel 6 W&H (working holiday) | Moab, US

2011/06-2011/11

• US Working Holiday project(J1 visa). Co-work with American, Mexican, Indian, Russian, China, and Turks.